What if your project management tool
wasn't just for managing projects? What
if it could act as a messenger, a
central command center, and an
automation engine all at once? Well,
here comes the good news. With Fleno
boards supporting outgoing web hooks, it
[music] now more than possible. You can
now seamlessly connect Flenboards to
Slack, Microsoft Teams, Discord,
Telegram, or any other tool you can
think of. And to make it simple, this
tutorial will show you how to connect
Flen Boards with Telegram. So, let's
dive in.
Search for bot father and type the
common/ newbot to create a new one.
Following the message, let's write a
name for the bot.
And here comes the credentials you need.
Let's copy the bot token and add it to
the group or channel where the
notifications are to appear.
Well, the first step is done
successfully. In this step, we'll need
an automation tool like Zapier, make.com
or naden. So for this tutorial we are
going with Zapier. Once you open Zapier
you will see the zap right there. Tap on
it and pick web hook as the trigger
and the trigger event will be a catch
hook. Skipping the configure option.
Let's move on to the test. This is
perfect to see whether the web hook will
function perfectly or not. It works. So
let's copy the link for now. There's
another step left. But before that let's
quickly set up the web hook URL in
Flintboards. Uh moving into the fl board
settings uh you can easily spot incoming
and outgoing web hooks. Now uh to set
the new web hook, I'll click on the add
new button. So let's start by giving our
web hook a unique name. The next thing
is the payload URL. That's where we need
to paste the URL we just created in
Zapier. Now pick the board and choose
the triggers when the flow will be
activated. And of course save the
changes. Well, our work is done here.
Now let's get back to Zapier. The event
trigger is set. It's time to set the
action. So let's go for telegram. Uh as
I want to receive a message whenever a
task is created or any other action
occurs in Flintboards. Uh let's select
the action trigger
send message. The account selection is
crucial. Uh if I tap on the box, it will
take me to another page where I can
provide the bot token. We have created
the bot earlier. So all I need to do is
paste the B code.
Here you go. The account is connected.
The chat ID is selected already and the
text format is as it is. Remember the
message text is very important because
uh this is the thing that will reach
your account. So make sure it's perfect.
We have got an option to run a test
here, but let's skip it and see it for
real. It's time to publish the web hook
and see it in action.
Let's create a task on the board we
connected with telegram and ureka. As
you can see just as I create a new task
and notification pops up instantly in my
telegram.
So from now on everything will be in
sync and with every change I'll get an
instant notification without having to
visit the board each time. With this
setup you will never have to ask what's
the latest update again. So from now on
flboards is powerful than ever.
Flintboards keeps everyone in sync
automatically using an outgoing web
hook. So go ahead, set it up once and
watch your workflow run on autopilot.
Don't forget to grab Floboards to
simplify your project management in
WordPress like never before. Grab it
now.